{
    "id": "af032ee015654008a52432ce6eb48bf7",
    "title": "Expect, Hope and Wait | Exercise",
    "exercises": [
        {
            "id": "e23f70366bf94176af056135195bd88e",
            "title": "Expect, Hope and Wait",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "She is ……………… a promotion.",
                    "description": "Before a noun we use hope for or wait for. Expect is used without for.",
                    "answers": [
                        "waiting",
                        "hoping",
                        "expecting"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "I am ………………… Maria to come in the evening.",
                    "description": "If we expect something to happen we have a good reason to believe that it will happen.",
                    "answers": [
                        "expecting",
                        "hoping",
                        "waiting"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "I am ………………… to hear from her.",
                    "description": "All three of these verbs are possible before a to-infinitive with somewhat similar meanings.  ",
                    "answers": [
                        "waiting",
                        "hoping",
                        "expecting",
                        "All of the above"
                    ],
                    "correct": 3
                },
                {
                    "question": "He ……………….. to get a bike for his birthday.",
                    "description": "Either hopes or expects is possible here.",
                    "answers": [
                        "hopes",
                        "expects",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "I have been ………………. for her for hours.",
                    "description": "We wait when somebody or something is late.",
                    "answers": [
                        "waiting",
                        "hoping",
                        "expecting"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "She can’t ………………… for her birthday.",
                    "description": "Can’t wait shows impatience.",
                    "answers": [
                        "wait",
                        "hope",
                        "expect"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "We are ………………….. rain soon.",
                    "description": "Before a noun we use hope for or wait for. Expect is used without for.",
                    "answers": [
                        "expecting",
                        "hoping",
                        "waiting"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "We are ………………… to get good rains this year.",
                    "description": "Before a to-infinitive, all of the above are possible. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "hoping",
                        "expecting",
                        "waiting",
                        "All of the above"
                    ],
                    "correct": 3
                },
                {
                    "question": "She is quite shy. I ………………….. her to be smarter.",
                    "description": "Before object + infinitive we use hope for or wait for. Expect is used without for.",
                    "answers": [
                        "expected",
                        "hoped",
                        "waited"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "Employees are ………………… to start work at 9 o’clock.",
                    "description": "Expect is often used with object + infinitive to talk about people’s duties. Passive forms of this structure are also common.",
                    "answers": [
                        "expected",
                        "hoped",
                        "waited"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "We are …………………. that you can come and stay with us.",
                    "description": "Progressive forms of expect are not normally used before a that-clause.",
                    "answers": [
                        "hoping",
                        "expecting",
                        "waiting"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "We ………………. to hear from her today.",
                    "description": "Before a to-infinitive simple and continuous forms of hope and expect are used with very similar meanings.",
                    "answers": [
                        "hope",
                        "expect",
                        "are hoping",
                        "are expecting",
                        "All of the above"
                    ],
                    "correct": 4
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}